The Bailey Collection
The Bailey Collection
- Documents relating to Stretford and Flixton, 16th century-19th century; GB/418/C.7.22 & C.7.23; GB/418/Bailey/4; Chetham's Library
  - Correspondence concerning the history of Flixton., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.23 (13); GB/418/Bailey/4/24; Chetham's Library
  - Copy of theEccles and District Advertiser., 7 Jul 1883; GB/418/C.7.23 (14); GB/418/Bailey/4/25; Chetham's Library
    Eccles and District Advertiser
  - Appeal for the restoration of the Church of the Holy Rood, Spersholt, Banks., [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.23 (15); GB/418/Bailey/4/26; Chetham's Library
    Annotated by Bailey.
  - Report of Stretford Mission Church and Infant School., 1883; GB/418/C.7.23 (16); GB/418/Bailey/4/27; Chetham's Library
  - Advertisement forTrafford Park Illustrated., 1884; GB/418/C.7.23 (17); GB/418/Bailey/4/28; Chetham's Library
    Trafford Park Illustrated
  - Fire insurance certificate relating to the property of John Sherlock of Ashton upon Mersey., 1808; GB/418/C.7.23 (18); GB/418/Bailey/4/29; Chetham's Library
  - Grant from Peter Walkden to Francis Brundrett of a road from a close of land in Flixton called Ash Ryding., 24 Jan 1786; GB/418/C.7.23 (19); GB/418/Bailey/4/30; Chetham's Library
  - Henry Clarke,The School Candidates: a Prosaic Burlesque occasioned by the election of a schoolmaster at the Village of Stretford, near Manchester., (18 Jan 1788); GB/418/C.7.23 (20); GB/418/Bailey/4/31; Chetham's Library
    The School Candidates: a Prosaic Burlesque occasioned by the election of a schoolmaster at the Village of Stretford, near Manchester.
    Reprinted by J. E. Bailey, Manchester, 1876.
  - Bond from Richard Valentine of Baguley and Robert Brundrett of Flixton to Thomas Goldsworthy of Davyhulme., [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.23 (21); GB/418/Bailey/4/32; Chetham's Library
  - Account from John Bruntich to Samuel Wood., 1808; GB/418/C.7.23 (22); GB/418/Bailey/4/33; Chetham's Library
  - Probate of the will of John Brundrett of Chorlton., 24 Jul 1794; GB/418/C.7.23 (23); GB/418/Bailey/4/34; Chetham's Library
  - Bundle of miscellaneous papers relating to the estate of John Brundrett of Chorlton., [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.23 (24); GB/418/Bailey/4/35; Chetham's Library
  - Folder containing miscellaneous documents relating to Flixton., [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.23 (25); GB/418/Bailey/4/36; Chetham's Library
  - Envelope containing papers relating mostly to life of Henry Clark, Schoolmaster of Stretford., [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.23 (26); GB/418/Bailey/4/37; Chetham's Library
  - Bond in £100 from Richard Wright to Edward Stelfox., 8 Dec 1817; GB/418/C.7.23 (27); GB/418/Bailey/4/38; Chetham's Library
  - Bond in £60 from Benjamin Jameson to John Gerrard., [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.23 (28); GB/418/Bailey/4/39; Chetham's Library
  - Probate copy of the will of John Darbyshire., 21 Jul 1798; GB/418/C.7.23 (29); GB/418/Bailey/4/40; Chetham's Library
  - Receipt for £10 from James and Sarah Darbyshire to George Ashton., [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.23 (30); GB/418/Bailey/4/41; Chetham's Library
  - Details of the mismanagement of affairs of Stretford Gas Company., 4 Mar 1880; GB/418/C.7.23 (31); GB/418/Bailey/4/42; Chetham's Library
  - Notice of the laying of the memorial stone of All Saints Mission Church, Stretford., 1884; GB/418/C.7.23 (32); GB/418/Bailey/4/43; Chetham's Library
  - Bundle of miscellaneous notes and cuttings relating to the history of Stretford., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.23 (33); GB/418/Bailey/4/44; Chetham's Library
  - Duchy of Lancaster pleadings relating to Stretford., (1594-1602); GB/418/C.7.23 (34); GB/418/Bailey/4/45; Chetham's Library
- Lancashire Assessment of 1641 and miscellaneous notes, 17th century-19th century; GB/418/C.7.24 nos 1-11 & C.7.25; GB/418/Bailey/5; Chetham's Library
  - Original manuscript of the 1641 tax assessment for the Manchester area., GB/418/C.7.24 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/5/1; Chetham's Library
    Incomplete and excludes Manchester itself. 17 documents:
    I. Broughton, Kersal, Tetlow.
    II. Pendleton.
    III. Urmston.
    IV. Pilkington.
    V. Flixton.
    VI. Salford.
    VII. Clifton.
    VIII. Pendlebury.
    IX. Withington, Fallowfield, Rusholme, Moss Side, Didsbury, Levenshulme.
    X. Worsley, Swinton, Boothstown, Little Hulton.
    XI. Chorton-cum-Hardy.
    XII. Haughton.
    XIII. Prestwich, Heaton, Heaton-upon-Faughfield, Alkrington, Tonge.
    XIV. Chadderton.
    XV. Royton.
    XVI. Crompton.
    XVII. Oldham.
    Notes
    The assessment was compiled following the Act of Parliament entitled An act for the speedie provision of money for the disbanding of the armies following the peace of the two kingdoms of England and Scotland, August 1641. (Printed version - Wing E 1130.)
    Those parts of the manuscript relating to the townships of Oldham, Chadderton, Royton and Crompton were reprinted in Giles Shaw,Annals of Oldham(Oldham, 1904). The entry for Crompton is also reproduced in Elsie Ballard,A Chronicle of Crompton (1967), pp. 34-37.
    The work is Lot No. 2445: Names of persons to be assessed in Oldham, Chadderton, Royton, Crompton, Shaw, Prestwich, Pendleton, Pilkington, Chorlton-cum-Hardy, Haughton, Withington, Clifton, Pendlebury, Worsley, Urmston etc. 1641, Original Lists. Catalogue of the valuable and extensive Library of the late John Eglington Bailey …sold by auction, by Capes, Dunn and Pilcher Monday, June 24th 1889 and five following days.
  - Volume of Bailey's notes on baptisms, marriages and burials of Lancashire clergymen., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.24 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/5/2; Chetham's Library
  - 19th century manuscript summary of Church Survey from Lansdowne MS no. 459, Manchester, Salford Hundred, Lonsdale Hundred, Derby Hundred., (c 1650); GB/418/C.7.24 no 3; GB/418/Bailey/5/3; Chetham's Library
  - List of nonconformist meeting houses in Lancashire licensed in pursuance of the Declaration of Indulgence., (1672); GB/418/C.7.24 no 4; GB/418/Bailey/5/4; Chetham's Library
    19th century transcript. In alphabetical order of place name.
  - List of nonconformist meeting houses in Lancashire licensed in pursuance of the Declaration of Indulgence., (1672); GB/418/C.7.24 no 5; GB/418/Bailey/5/5; Chetham's Library
    19th century transcript extracted directly from the State Papers in the order in which the licences appear.
  - List of nonconformist meeting houses in Cheshire licensed in pursuance of the Declaration of Indulgence., (1672); GB/418/C.7.24 no 6; GB/418/Bailey/5/6; Chetham's Library
  - Extracts from State Papers temp Charles I relating to ecclesiastical matters., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.24 no 7; GB/418/Bailey/5/7; Chetham's Library
  - Miscellaneous notes from Royalist Composition papers., [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.24 no 8; GB/418/Bailey/5/8; Chetham's Library
  - Miscellaneous notes from plundered ministers' accounts., [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.24 no 9; GB/418/Bailey/5/9; Chetham's Library
  - Bundle of newspaper cuttings., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.24 no 10; GB/418/Bailey/5/10; Chetham's Library
  - Miscellaneous sheets of notes by Bailey., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.24 no 11; GB/418/Bailey/5/11; Chetham's Library
    Some in shorthand.
- Miscellaneous notes, transcripts and original documents, 16th century-19th century; GB/418/C.7.26, 29, 39, 40, 41, 42, 43; GB/418/Bailey/6; Chetham's Library
  - Notebook compiled by J. E. Bailey., [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/6/1; Chetham's Library
    Notebook containing notes on various subjects:
    i) ‘Extracts from Torporley Register from MS penes [John] Arden of Stockport, Esq., 1769’: being a list of marriages and burials taken from the parish registers of Tarporley.
    ii) ‘Epitaph drawn up at the request of John Kay Hatfeild by me John Watson, Stockport, 1770. (Latin).
    iii) ‘Manuscripts penes John Arden of Stockport, Esq., besides those relating to Cheshire’, being a list of manuscripts and pedigrees largely relating to Lancashire.
    iv) ‘MS B[oo]k Y[or]ks[hire] families in Watson MSS’ being notes on various families.
    v) ‘A short refutation of some cheife pointes in Mr Burne his sermons latelie preached in Manchester’, being a discussion of the sermons of The Rev. William Burne.
    vi) ‘Arden MS (continued)’ being a further list of the manuscripts in the possession of John Arden.
    a) A copy of the memoryall which Sir Walter Aston the Ambassador of the Kynge of G[rea]t Britayne have his Majestie of Spayne the 29th of July 1624’.
    b) A discourse ‘whereby it is endeavoured to prove that it would be lawfull to subscribe to the Engagement of the present powers were usurpers (as is pretended by the Dissenters) and this notwithstanding the Covenant on anie other preingagements’.
    c) ‘News from Scotland’, being an account of what passed after the Marquis of Hamilton was returned into England.
    d) ‘Contains a pedigree of Marbury’.
    e) ‘Dr Abdie Assheton’s letter concerning the Earl of Essex’.
    vii) Extracts from the Parish Registers of Prestbury, such as Burials (1562, 1642, 16531721), Weddings (1574-1721), and Christenings (1561-1688).
    viii) Copy of a letter from ‘Per: Towneley’, 7 Park St, Westminster, to Charles Blundell, Esq., Ince, Liverpool, dated 15 May 1823. The letter relates to ‘a copy of the extract from the Towneley Mysteries selected for the purpose of presentation to the Roxburgh Club by Mr Douce’.
    ix) ‘An Act for repairing and amending the Road leading from the Town of Manchester in the Co[unty] Pal[atine] of Lanc[aster] thro[ugh] the town of Ashton-under-Lyne and the parish of Mottram-[in]-Long[d]endale, and from thence to Salter’s Brook in the co[unty] Pal[atine] of Chester’. The list of trustees includes 93 names.
    Act for repairing the road from Manchester to Salter’s Brook with a long list of trustees, 1732.
  - Large bundle of manuscript transcriptions of notices of births, marriages and death fromThe Gentleman's Magazine., (1734-1859); GB/418/C.7.26 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/6/2; Chetham's Library
    Apparently extracted by D. Bennett and sent to Bailey in 1884.
  - List of references to Lancashire and Cheshire in the Calendar of State Papers., (16th century and 17th century); GB/418/C.7.26 no 3; GB/418/Bailey/6/3; Chetham's Library
  - List of Manchester Recusants in State Papers., (1584); GB/418/C.7.26 no 4; GB/418/Bailey/6/4; Chetham's Library
  - Extracts from Bucklow Hundred subsidy roll relating to recusants in Cheshire., (1663); GB/418/C.7.26 no 5; GB/418/Bailey/6/5; Chetham's Library
  - References to Lancashire people and places in State Papers., (13th century-15th century); GB/418/C.7.26 no 6; GB/418/Bailey/6/6; Chetham's Library
  - Details of burials of clergymen recorded in various Lancashire parish registers, including that of Manchester Collegiate Church, 16th century-18th century; GB/418/C.7.26 no 7; GB/418/Bailey/6/7; Chetham's Library
    Tied to another manuscript containing details of burials of Lancashire clerks and schoolmasters.
  - List of subscribers in Lancashire to various books., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 8; GB/418/Bailey/6/8; Chetham's Library
    No book titles given.
  - A Map entitled ‘Lancashire North from London’ detailing the county’s representation in Parliament, its boroughs and market towns, as well as details of the most important towns, their markets and fairs. The map was ‘publish’d by the proprietor W. H. Toms, Sept. 29. 1742’., GB/418/C.7.26 no 9; GB/418/Bailey/6/9; Chetham's Library
  - List of subscribers to John Gore'sArithmetic Fairly laid Open, (Liverpool, 1769)., GB/418/C.7.26 no 10; GB/418/Bailey/6/10; Chetham's Library
    Arithmetic Fairly laid Open
  - Letters concerning Lancashire dialect song., 1881; GB/418/C.7.26 no 11; GB/418/Bailey/6/11; Chetham's Library
  - Letter from H. J. Popplewell concerning deeds relating to Lancashire and Cheshire., 1882; GB/418/C.7.26 no 12; GB/418/Bailey/6/12; Chetham's Library
  - Notes on commissions relating to prominent Lancashire clergy in the Commonwealth period., [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 13; GB/418/Bailey/6/13; Chetham's Library
  - 19th century transcription of a notice concerning the theft of the Lancashire Duchy Seal., (1644); GB/418/C.7.26 no 14; GB/418/Bailey/6/14; Chetham's Library
  - Note on Lancashire Jesuits., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 15; GB/418/Bailey/6/15; Chetham's Library
  - List of Knights from Lancashire and Cheshire chosen by Charles II for investiture under the Royal Oak., (17th century); GB/418/C.7.26 no 16; GB/418/Bailey/6/16; Chetham's Library
  - List of subscribers to Enfield'sHistory of Liverpool., 1774; GB/418/C.7.26 no 17; GB/418/Bailey/6/17; Chetham's Library
    History of Liverpool.
  - Published handlist of Lancashire and Cheshire artists., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 18; GB/418/Bailey/6/18; Chetham's Library
  - Notes on Lancashire archers at Flodden., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 19; GB/418/Bailey/6/19; Chetham's Library
  - Notes on Lancashire churches in the 13th century., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 20; GB/418/Bailey/6/20; Chetham's Library
  - Lists of Lancashire troops., (1690 & 1691); GB/418/C.7.26 no 21; GB/418/Bailey/6/21; Chetham's Library
    Tanscribed in the 19th century.
  - List of published funeral sermons relating to Lancashire clergy., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 22; GB/418/Bailey/6/22; Chetham's Library
  - Notes on Lancashire churches in 1600., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 23; GB/418/Bailey/6/23; Chetham's Library
  - Transcript of receipts of loan monies in Lancashire from Richard Asshton., (1570); GB/418/C.7.26 no 24; GB/418/Bailey/6/24; Chetham's Library
    19th century transcript.
  - Transcript from the Cecil papers concerning the government of Cheshire., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 25; GB/418/Bailey/6/25; Chetham's Library
  - Lists of subscribers to several books and notes on various villages in Lancashire., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 26; GB/418/Bailey/6/26; Chetham's Library
  - List of nobility related to the county of Lancaster., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 27; GB/418/Bailey/6/27; Chetham's Library
  - Notes on 16th century recusants and papists in Lancashire., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.26 no 28; GB/418/Bailey/6/28; Chetham's Library
  - Large collection of manuscript notes made by J. E. Bailey in connection with his publicationsInventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire, taken in the year A.D. 1552, pt.1: Salford Hundred(1879), andpt.2: West Derby, Blackburn and Leyland Hundreds (1888), Chetham Society, Old Series, vols 107 and 113., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.40 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/6/29; Chetham's Library
    Inventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire, taken in the year A.D. 1552, pt.1: Salford Hundred; pt.2: West Derby, Blackburn and Leyland Hundreds
    Relates mostly to church plate and vestments in Lancashire.
  - Book of notes on definitions of types of church plate and vestments compiled by J. E. Bailey., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.40 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/6/30; Chetham's Library
  - Corrected proofs of pages 1-8 of J. E. Bailey'sInventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.40 no 3; GB/418/Bailey/6/31; Chetham's Library
    Inventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire.
    Chetham Society, Old Series, vols 107 (1879) and 113 (1888).
  - Annotated unbound copy of pages 1-104 of J. E. Bailey'sInventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.40 no 4; GB/418/Bailey/6/32; Chetham's Library
    Inventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire
    Chetham Society, Old Series, vols 107 and 113.
  - Transcriptions of original documents relating to the confiscation of church goods in Lancashire, temp Edw VI., (16th century); GB/418/C.7.40 no 5; GB/418/Bailey/6/33; Chetham's Library
  - Slips prepared by J. E. Bailey in connection with his index toInventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.40 no 6; GB/418/Bailey/6/34; Chetham's Library
  - Folder of miscellaneous notes and correspondence concerning church goods., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.40 no 7; GB/418/Bailey/6/35; Chetham's Library
  - Bundle of advertisements for books mostly from theAthanaeum, theSaturday ReviewandThe Times, with notes by J. E. Bailey on books ordered by him., 1879-1883; GB/418/C.7.41 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/6/36; Chetham's Library
    Athanaeum; Saturday Review; The Times
  - Bundle of extracts from newspapers relating to miscellaneous subjects., 1870-1875; GB/418/C.7.41 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/6/37; Chetham's Library
  - Bundle of newspaper cuttings relating to a wide variety of subjects., 1860s-1870s; GB/418/C.7.41 no 3; GB/418/Bailey/6/38; Chetham's Library
  - Brief descriptions of medieval Trafford deeds., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.41 no 4; GB/418/Bailey/6/39; Chetham's Library
  - Large bundle of newspaper cuttings relating to a wide variety of broadly historical subjects., 1860s-1880s; GB/418/C.7.42; GB/418/Bailey/6/40; Chetham's Library
  - A letter from Mr Janvillo, Cologne, to the King [Charles II], dated at Cologne, 24 Feb 1678, declaring that he had seen a vision relating to His Majesty’s affairs. (French)., GB/418/C.7.43 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/6/41; Chetham's Library
  - ‘A Faithfull Registre of the Debates of the House of Commons in 3 Parliament[s]’ (held at Westminster 1680, at Oxford, 1680, and at Westminster, 1685) concerning the Bill of Exclusion., (1680 & 1685); GB/418/C.7.43 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/6/42; Chetham's Library
    These are extracts from the debates relating to this Bill.
  - Notes relating to various medieval deeds., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.43 no 3; GB/418/Bailey/6/43; Chetham's Library
    A deed [undated] whereby Sybil, daughter and heir of William del Pers granted to Plympton Priory, Devon, the fishing rights at Plaistow and Buckland, Devon. ‘Extracts from Mr Heywood’s old deed’, mentioning a deed relating to Gilbert de Ferrers, his mother Sybil del Pin, and her grant to Plympton Priory. Further notes relate to another deed concerning John de Ferrers, a descendant of Gilbert Ferrers, and the fishing rights granted to Plympton Priory, dated 43 Edward III [1369/70].
  - Abstracts of duplicates in the Kings Remembrancer's office., 1650s; GB/418/C.7.43 no 4; GB/418/Bailey/6/44; Chetham's Library
    ‘An abstract of the duplicates in the king’s remembrancer’s office of the numbers of houses upon new foundations in the parishes within the weekly bills of mortality without London return’d thiche in persuance of the Act concerning new buildings pass’d in the yeare 1656: together with the sums of mon[e]y charged on each parish by the commissioner thereunto appoynted at a full yeares alew of the improved rent of the sayd houses’. 1659 or 1677.
  - Notes entitled ‘Antiqu. Britann. Hibern. Angl. Saxon. etc’, being extracts from Nicholson, Olaus Wormius, Aub. Miroeus, etc., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.43 no 5; GB/418/Bailey/6/45; Chetham's Library
  - Notes entitled ‘Ex Rymer Collect. Vol. III’ being extracts from Thomas Rymer’sFoedera (1704-13), volumes III, IV, and V, relating to the reigns of Edward II and Edward III., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.43 no 6; GB/418/Bailey/6/46; Chetham's Library
    Foedera
  - Notes on a manuscript held in the Harleian Library, being the autobiography of the antiquary Sir Simond D’Ewes (1602-50)., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.43 no 7; GB/418/Bailey/6/47; Chetham's Library
    Extracts relate to the ancestry of the Basset family of Weldon.
  - Notes entitled ‘From the 1st volume of Pryn’s Ecclesiastical Power of the Saxon Kings and their successors’, being extracts from W. Prynne’sEcclesiastical Power of the Saxon Kings., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.43 no 8; GB/418/Bailey/6/48; Chetham's Library
    Ecclesiastical Power of the Saxon Kings
  - Notes on parliamentary writs from the reign of Edward II to the reign of Edward IV being extracts from W. Prynne’sBrevia Parliamentoria Rediviva (1662)., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.43 no 9; GB/418/Bailey/6/49; Chetham's Library
    Brevia Parliamentoria Rediviva
    The first part of a brief register, kalendar and survey of the several kinds, forms of all parliamentary writs:: comprising ... / By William Prynne Esq; a Bencher of Lincolnes Inne
    SeeThe first part of a brief register, kalendar and survey of the several kinds, forms of all parliamentary writs:: comprising ... / By William Prynne Esq; a Bencher of Lincolnes Inne (London, 1659), and [?three] further parts.
  - Extracts fromThe happy future state of England by Sir Peter Pett (1630-1699), (London, [1688])., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.43 no 10; GB/418/Bailey/6/50; Chetham's Library
    The happy future state of England
  - Errors and defects in William Camden's (1551-1623)Britannia: or, A chorographical description of Great Britain and Ireland, together with the adjacent islands. / Written in Latin by William Camden, Clarenceux King at arms, (London, first printed in 1607)., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.43 no 11; GB/418/Bailey/6/51; Chetham's Library
    Britannia: or, A chorographical description of Great Britain and Ireland, together with the adjacent islands. / Written in Latin by William Camden, Clarenceux King at arms
  - Notes entitled ‘Collect. Ex MSS Epistolis Gualteri, Bullengeri, etc, ad Epos Anglie tempore Elizabetha’, being Letters from Walter, Bullengeri, the epic poem in English of the era of Elizabeth I., (16th century); GB/418/C.7.43 no 12; GB/418/Bailey/6/52; Chetham's Library
    19th century transcription.
  - Notes fromThe antiquities of Canterbury by William Somner and Nicolas Battely (London, 1703)., nd [19th century]; GB/418/C.7.43 no 13; GB/418/Bailey/6/53; Chetham's Library
    The antiquities of Canterbury
    The antiquities of Canterbury.: In two parts. The first part. The antiquities of Canterbury; or a survey of that ancient city, with the suburbs and cathedral, &c. Sought out and published by the industry and good will of William Somner. The second edition, revised and enlarged by Nicolas Battely, M.A. also Mr. Somner's Discourse called Chartham-News: Or a relation of some strange bones found at Chartham in Kent. To which are added some observations concerning the Roman antiquities of Canterbury. And a preface, giving an account of the works and remains of the learned antiquary Mr. William Somner, by N.B. The second part. Cantuaria sacra: or the antiquities I. Of the Cathedral and metropolitical church. II. Of the Archbishoprick. III. Of the late Priory of Christ-Church; and of the present Collegiate Church, founded by K. Hen. VIII. With a catalogue of all the Deans and Canons thereof. IV. Of the Monastery of St. Augustin; of the parish-churches, hospitals, and other religious places, that are or have been in or near that city; / enquired into, by Nicholas Battely, Vicar of Beaksborn. Illustrated and adorned with several useful and fair sculptures.